The celebration of a lifetime.
Coco is a family, animation, music film directed by Lee Unkrich.
Despite his family’s baffling generations-old ban on music, Miguel dreams of
becoming an accomplished musician like his idol, Ernesto de la Cruz.
Desperate to prove his talent, Miguel finds himself in the stunning and
colorful Land of the Dead following a mysterious chain of events.
Along the way, he meets charming trickster Hector, and together, they set off on an
extraordinary journey to unlock the real story behind Miguel's family history.
Miguel Rivera (voice), played by Anthony Gonzalez.
Héctor (voice), played by Gael García Bernal.
Ernesto de la Cruz (voice), played by Benjamin Bratt.
Mamá Imelda (voice), played by Alanna Ubach.
Abuelita (voice), played by Renée Victor.
Papá (voice), played by Jaime Camil.
Coco is a 2017 American animated fantasy comedy-drama film produced by
Pixar Animation Studios and released by Walt Disney Pictures.
It was directed by Lee Unkrich, co-directed by
Adrian Molina, and produced by Darla K.
Anderson, from a screenplay written by Molina and Matthew Aldrich, and a story developed by
Unkrich, Molina, Aldrich, and Jason Katz, based on an original idea conceived by Unkrich.
The film stars the voices of Anthony Gonzalez, Gael García Bernal, Benjamin Bratt,
Alanna Ubach, Renée Victor, Ana Ofelia Murguía and Edward James Olmos.
It follows a 12-year-old boy in Mexico named Miguel (Gonzalez) who is accidentally transported to the Land of the Dead, where he seeks
the help of his deceased musician great-great-grandfather to return him to his family and reverse their ban on music.
The concept for Coco is inspired by the Mexican holiday Day of the Dead.
Pixar began developing the animation in 2016.
Unkrich, Molina, Anderson and some of the film's
crew visited Mexico for research.
Composer Michael Giacchino, who had worked on prior Pixar
animated features, composed the score.
With a cost of $175–225 million, Coco is the first film with a
nine-figure budget to feature an all-Latino principal cast.
Coco premiered on October 20, 2017, during the Morelia
International Film Festival in Morelia, Mexico.
It was theatrically released in Mexico the following week, the weekend before
Día de Muertos, and in the United States on November 22, 2017.
The film received acclaim for its animation, voice acting, music,
visuals, emotional story, and respect for Mexican culture.
It grossed over $814 million worldwide, becoming the 15th
highest-grossing animated film ever at the time of its release.
Coco received two awards at the 90th Academy
Awards and numerous other accolades.
The film was chosen by the National Board of Review
as the Best Animated Film of 2017.
A sequel, titled Coco 2, is currently in development.
The film explores themes of skeleton, mexico, guitar, afterlife, musician.